VAGGELIS CHANIOTAKIS

MSc. Software | Data Engineer



chaniotakisv@gmail.com



Heraklion, Crete, Greece



SUMMARY

Highly motivated Software Engineer with working experience in the fields of information systems, research and development and data engineering, providing high-level support to multiple projects. Equipped with a theoretical and practical background in data management, big data analytics and mobile software development, I can contribute to real-world problems and give data-driven solutions.

EDUCATION

University of Crete, CSD

(MSc) Master in Computer Science and Engineering

Grade: 9

Master Thesis:

A Scalable Data Science Platform, Based on Open Source Technologies with a Predictive Analytics Application for Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Disease

Technological Educational Institute of Crete

(BSc) Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering

Grade: 7,5

Thesis:

Development of Android Application for the management of purchases and sales

SKILLS

- Big Data Analytics
- Apache Spark, Scala
- SQL, Spark SQL/ML Python learning
- Data Integration/ETL Git, Github, Gitlab
- MySQL, PSQL
- Flutter, Dart
- Java Spring Boot learning

- Linux, Windows
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js Learning
 - The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp (Udemy Learning)
- Teaching (Professor's Assistant) C, C++ courses
- Strong organizational and time-management
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a
- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English (C2)
 - London Tests of English Level 5 (PROFICIENT COMMUNICATION) University of Westminster

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Business Administrator

09/2023 - 12/2023

Trade and Development Company

Software Engineer

02/2022 - 08/2023

Foundation for Research and Technology - Hellas (FORTH), Institute of Computer Science - Computational BioMedicine Laboratory

- Mobile software development for smart devices (Android, iOS)
- Participation in 3 European projects for Biomedical smart application development, data management and data analytics
 - ODIN (www.odin-smarthospitals.eu)
 - CARDIOCARE (www.cardiocare-project.eu)
 - TIMELY (www.timely-project.com)

Software | Data Engineer

11/2019 - 03/2021

Foundation for Research and Technology - Hellas (FORTH), Institute of Computer Science - Computational BioMedicine Laboratory

- Design and development of scalable data infrastructures for the efficient storage, management and predictive analytics of multimodal clinical data, in the context of Bio-Medical study and Laboratory support
 - In particular I designed and developed entirely a scalable platform for managing large volumes of data, based exclusively on open source technologies
 - Successfully published in the IEEE 34th International Conference on Computer-Based Medical Systems (https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9474687)
- Prepared and presented scientific reports and presentations

Software Developer

07/2019 - 09/2019

Omnixell - Science and Technology Park of Crete (STEP-C)

Web Development for cross-platform applications using Ionic 3 and Angular

Software Engineer Intern

10/2017 - 04/2018

Foundation for Research and Technology - Hellas (FORTH), Institute of Computer Science - Computational BioMedicine Laboratory

- Research and development in BioMedical scenarios
- Publication in the IEEE EMBS International Conference on Biomedical & Health Informatics, Las Vegas, NV, USA
 - https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8333454

PUBLICATIONS

International Conference Papers

- Predictive Analytics Based on Open Source Technologies for Acute Respiratory Distress SyndromePredictive Analytics Based on Open Source Technologies for Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome
 - IEEE 34th International Symposium on Computer-Based Medical Systems (CBMS) · Jul 8, 2021
 - https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9474687
- Evaluation of Head Pose Features for Stress Detection and ClassificationEvaluation of Head Pose Features for Stress Detection and Classification
 - o IEEE EMBS International Conference on Biomedical & Health Informatics (BHI), Las Vegas, NV, USA · Mar 4, 2018
 - https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8333454

SEMINARS AND CERTIFICATES

SEMINARS | CONFERENCES | CERTIFICATES

- Microsoft Certificate at Career Essentials in Data Analysis (Microsoft and LinkedIn), 2024
- Big Data Analytics with Hadoop and Apache Spark (LinkedIn Learning), 2024
- Data Engineering | Azure | Google Cloud Platform | Apache Kafka Learning | Python for Data Engineering (LinkedIn), 2024
- IEEE 34th International Symposium on Computer-Based Medical Systems (CBMS) · Jul 8, 2021
- Certificate of Continuing Education Completion in CompTIA Linux+ (CYBRARY.IT), 2017
- Certificate of Continuing Education Completion in Secure Coding (CYBRARY.IT), 2017
- Certificate of Continuing Education Completion in Project Management Professional (PMP) (CYBRARY.IT), 2017
- Certificate of Continuing Education Completion in Office 365 Web Content Management (CYBRARY.IT), 2017
- Devstaff (The Developers Community Gathering in Crete) Thematic speeches: Unit Testing, Mobile Development, Secure Development, Business & StartUps, Dessign Patterns, NoSQL, Building scalable apps and working with large scale systems, CMS, TOR, Remote Working etc. (FORTH 2015 2019)

HONORS AND AWARDS

Master of Science Scholarship

- Issued by Foundation for Research and Technology Hellas (FORTH) Institute of Computer Science (ICS)
 - November 2019

MILITARY SERVICE

Greek Army - Airborne Army Forces

03/2021 - 12/2021

- · Command Office Assistant (IT Services)
- Management of money transactions